How do they solve a mystery when they don't have a clue?
Looney Tunes: Back in Action is a animation, comedy,
family film directed by Joe Dante.
Fed up with all the attention going to Bugs Bunny, Daffy Duck quits
Hollywood, teams up with recently-fired stuntman Damien Drake Jr.
and embarks on a round-the-world adventure, along
with Bugs and The VP of Warner Bros.
Their mission?
Find Damien's father, and the missing blue diamond...
and stay one step ahead of The Acme Corp., who wants
the diamond for their own purposes.
DJ Drake / Tasmanian Devil (voice) / She-Devil
(voice) / Self, played by Brendan Fraser.
Kate, played by Jenna Elfman.
Mr. Chairman, played by Steve Martin.
Bugs Bunny-Daffy Duck / Beaky Buzzard / Sylvester /
Mama Bear (voice), played by Joe Alaskey.
Yosemite Sam / Foghorn Leghorn / Nasty Canasta (voice), played by Jeff Bennett.
Damien Drake, played by Timothy Dalton.
Looney Tunes: Back in Action is a 2003 American live-action animated
comedy film directed by Joe Dante and written by Larry Doyle.
The film stars Brendan Fraser, Jenna Elfman and Steve Martin, with Timothy
Dalton, Joan Cusack, and Heather Locklear in supporting roles.
A parody of action and spy films, the plot follows Looney Tunes characters Bugs Bunny and Daffy Duck as they become intertwined in a plot by
the Acme Corporation's chairman to transform the world's population into subservient monkeys using the Blue Monkey diamond.
They accompany aspiring stuntman DJ Drake and Warner Bros.
executive Kate Houghton on their journey to thwart the chairman's plot, which
doubles as a mission to rescue the former's abducted father, Damian.
The film was the result of multiple attempts by Warner Bros.
to develop a sequel to Space Jam (1996).
It was originally produced as Spy Jam, which was
intended to star Jackie Chan in the lead role.
Dante, out of a personal dislike for Space Jam, substantially developed the project to more closely represent the original personalities
of the Looney Tunes characters, with Walt Disney Animation Studios animator Eric Goldberg serving as animation director.
However, Dante reportedly had no creative control on the project, and
the final film became different from what he intended.
The film was the last project by Warner Bros.
Feature Animation and the final film scored by composer and Dante collaborator Jerry Goldsmith, who died
eight months following its release; John Debney composed additional material for the score.
Looney Tunes: Back in Action premiered on November 9, 2003, and was
theatrically released in the United States on November 14.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and was a box-office
failure, grossing $68 million on an $80 million budget.
Due to the film's financial failure, Warner Bros.
subsequently canceled several planned Looney Tunes
projects, including new theatrical short films.
At the 31st Annie Awards, the film was nominated for four
Annie Awards, including Best Animated Feature.
The film explores themes of diamond, bunny, spy, movie business, duck.
The tone is lighthearted.